Are you ready kids?
孩子们准备好了吗？
Children: Aye, aye, Captain!
孩子们：是啊是啊，队长！
I can't hear you!
我听不到你说话！
Children: Aye, aye, Captain!
孩子们：是啊是啊，队长！
♪ Ohh... ♪
♪ 哦...♪
♪ Who lives in a pineapple
under the sea? ♪
♪ 谁住在菠萝里
在海底？ ♪
Kids: ♪ SpongeBob SquarePants ♪
孩子们：♪ 海绵宝宝 ♪
Captain: ♪ Absorbent and yellow
and porous is he ♪
队长：♪ 吸水性的，黄色的
他是多孔的 ♪
Kids: ♪ SpongeBob SquarePants ♪
孩子们：♪ 海绵宝宝 ♪
Captain: ♪ If nautical nonsense
be somethin' you wish ♪
船长：♪ 如果是航海方面的废话
成为你所希望的那样 ♪
Kids: ♪ SpongeBob SquarePants ♪
孩子们：♪ 海绵宝宝 ♪
Captain: ♪ Then drop on the deck
and flop like a fish ♪
船长：♪ 然后降落在甲板上
然后像鱼一样扑通扑通♪
Kids: ♪ SpongeBob SquarePants ♪
孩子们：♪ 海绵宝宝 ♪
Captain: ♪ Ready? ♪
队长：♪ 准备好了吗？ ♪
All: ♪ SpongeBob SquarePants ♪
全部： ♪ 海绵宝宝 ♪
♪ SpongeBob SquarePants ♪
♪ 海绵宝宝 ♪
Captain: ♪ SpongeBob
SquarePants ♪
队长：♪ 海绵宝宝
方裤♪
good morning, Gary.
早上好，加里。
Meow.
喵。
Say, Gary, do you ever
wonder what Patrick's
mornings are like?
说，加里，你有没有
想知道帕特里克的是什么
早晨是什么样的？
Huh?
啊？
What?
什么？
Aah!
啊啊！
Aah...!
啊啊……！
What's making that noise?
是什么发出这种声音？
Oh, it's you again.
噢，又是你。
O.K., jokes over.
好吧，玩笑结束了。
All right, you got me...
好吧，你抓住了我...
Now cut it out.
现在把它剪掉。
That's it.
就是这样。
Stop your ringing, mister.
别再按铃了，先生。
I'm warning you.
我警告你。
Stop it!
停下来！
I said, quit it!
我说，放弃吧！
Oh?
哦？
Then where's it coming from?
那么它从哪里来呢？
Make it stop.
让它停止。
Buddy, you gotta help me
find out where that
ringing is coming from.
伙计，你一定要帮帮我
找出那个地方
铃声是从那里传来的。
Hey, come back!
嘿，回来吧！
Oh, fine, I'll ask
someone who cares.
哦，好的，我去问问
关心的人。
SpongeBob, where's
the ringing coming from?
海绵宝宝，在哪里
铃声从何而来？
Breakfast.
早餐。
Come to Patrick.
来帕特里克吧。
Tartar sauce.
鞑靼酱。
I'm out of food again.
我又没饭吃了
All I have are these lousy cans
我只有这些破罐头
with pictures of food on 'em.
上面有食物的图片。
I wanted real food,
not pictures.
我想要真正的食物，
不是图片。
Ooh...
哦...
The food is in the can.
食物在罐子里。
O.K., come on out.
好吧，出来吧。
Come on.
快点。
Oh, yeah.
哦，是的。
O.K., breakfast,
get on the plate.
好的，早餐，
上盘子。
Come on.
快点。
Nice comfy plate, just for you.
漂亮舒适的盘子，只为您而设计。
Come on, get on there.
来吧，上那儿。
Hello?
你好？
Anybody in there?
里面有人吗？
no answer.
没有答案。
I'm coming to rescue you!
我来救你了！
Having a little
trouble reaching you.
有一点
无法联系到您。
Stupid cans.
愚蠢的罐头。
Oh...
哦...
Food.
食物。
Ah, my favorite time of the day.
啊，一天中我最喜欢的时间。
Breakfast and a little
morning television.
早餐还有一点点
早间电视。
Announcer: And now, live from
Bikini Bottom, it's "Bikini
Bottom Live".
播音员：现在，直播
比基尼泳裤，它是“比基尼
底层生活”。
Oh, my gosh.
哦，天哪。
I'm late!
我来晚了！
I gotta put on my teeth and
brush my pants!
我必须戴上牙齿
擦我的裤子！
Ooh...!
噢...！
Gary?
加里？
Pants.
裤子。
A clean mouth is a happy mouth.
干净的嘴就是幸福的嘴。
Darn.
该死。
Hey, Patrick,
how was your morning?
嘿，帕特里克，
你早上过得怎么样？
Oh, you know, the usual.
哦，你知道，平常的。
What's this?
这是什么？
This is a free prize!
这是免费奖品！
Huh?
啊？
Where's my prize?
我的奖品在哪里？
Free prize...
免费奖品...
Offer inside!
里面优惠！
Just send in 99 box tops!
只需送99盒顶盖即可！
How ya doing over there, Gary?
加里，你在那儿怎么样？
Meow.
喵。
Send in the box tops
送入盒顶
before eating all the cereal?
在吃完所有谷物之前？
Gary, you are a genius!
加里，你是个天才！
I'm waiting.
我在等。
I'm waiting...
我在等...
Both: I'm waiting.
两人：我在等。
We're waiting.
我们正在等待。
SpongeBob?
海绵宝宝？
What're we waiting for?
我们还等什么？
We're waiting for the mailman.
我们正在等邮递员。
He's bringing me a free toy.
他给我带来了一个免费的玩具。
I love toys!
我喜欢玩具！
Can I wait for
your toy with you?
我可以等吗
你的玩具在你身边吗？
Why sure.
为什么肯定。
We're waiting.
我们正在等待。
There's the mailman!
邮递员来了！
You SpongeBob SquarePants?
你是海绵宝宝吗？
Yep.
是的。
Isn't there anything else?
难道就没有别的事了吗？
Nope.
没有。
Sorry, kid.
对不起，孩子。
Guess we'll have
to keep waiting.
猜猜我们会有
继续等待。
Hey, SpongeBob, I'm hungry.
嘿，海绵宝宝，我饿了。
Both:
两个都：
Me too.
我也是。
Let's go down to the Krusty
Krab for a Krabby Patty.
让我们去Krusty吧
蟹肉饼。
Great idea, Patrick.
好主意，帕特里克。
Krusty Krab, here we...
蟹堡王，我们...
Wait a minute!
等一下！
What if the mailman
comes when I'm gone?
如果邮递员怎么办
当我离开时来吗？
What's wrong, SpongeBob?
怎么了，海绵宝宝？
If I leave, the mailman might
come, and I might miss him.
如果我离开，邮递员可能会
来吧，我可能会想念他。
Oh, I'm gonna take off then.
哦，那我要走了。
I don't think my arm can stand
much more of this.
我觉得我的手臂无法站立
还有更多这样的事情。
Got to stay focused.
必须保持专注。
Hiya!
嗨！
Hey, SpongeBob,
wanna do some kara...
嘿，海绵宝宝，
想做点卡拉...
Not now, I'm busy.
现在不行，我很忙。
Oh, Gary, not now.
哦，加里，不是现在。
Can't you see that I'm
waiting for the mailman?
难道你看不出我是
等待邮递员？
Doesn't anyone understand this?
难道没有人明白这一点吗？
So tired...
这么累...
So hungry...
好饿……
But must wait for toy.
但必须等待玩具。
Hey, buddy.
嘿，伙计。
What?
什么？
What do you want?
你想要什么？
Can't you see I'm doing
something here?
你看不到我在做什么吗
这里有东西吗？
This better be good.
这最好是好的。
You missed your surprise
birthday party,
你错过了你的惊喜
生日聚会，
so I just wanted to bring you a
present and some cake,
所以我只是想给你带来一个
礼物和一些蛋糕，
'cause you missed it.
因为你错过了。
My birthday party?
我的生日聚会？
I missed my birthday party?
我错过了我的生日聚会吗？
Yeah... See?
是啊...看到了吗？
Here's a present and your cake.
这是一份礼物和你的蛋糕。
My birthday cake.
我的生日蛋糕。
Yeah, let me get you a fork,
so you can eat it.
是的，我给你拿把叉子，
所以你可以吃它。
Uh, let me just hold the cake
like this, so like I can get you
a fork.
呃，让我拿着蛋糕
就像这样，就像我能得到你一样
叉子。
Patrick: Huh.
帕特里克：嗯。
I wonder where I put that fork?
我想知道我把叉子放在哪里了？
Oops.
哎呀。
That was my cake.
那是我的蛋糕。
What is the present?
现在是什么？
Oh, yeah...
哦，是的...
The fork!
叉子！
That stupid toy!
那个愚蠢的玩具！
I wasted my whole
life waiting for it.
我浪费了我的全部
生活在等待着它。
Actually, you've
only been here 20 min...
事实上，你已经
只到这里20分钟...
I've been mean to Gary,
and I flipped Sandy.
我对加里很刻薄
我翻转了桑迪。
And now you hate me 'cause,
I'm a big jerk.
现在你恨我因为
我是个大混蛋。
No, I don't.
不，我不。
Yes, you do.
是的，你知道。
SpongeBob SquarePants?
海绵宝宝？
Could you come back later?
你能晚点回来吗？
He's having a moment.
他正在享受一段时光。
Yeah, I just need
his signature for...
是的，我只需要
他的签名为...
I said he's having a moment!
我说他有时间！
Now leave him alone!
现在别管他了！
No, Patrick...
不，帕特里克...
People like me don't
deserve moments.
像我这样的人不
值得的时刻。
I got so caught up in...
我是如此陷入...
Oh, here ya go.
哦，给你。
Waiting for my...
等待着我的...
My toy!
我的玩具！
Whoo!
呼！
Whoo, yeah!
呼，是啊！
Patrick, are you thinkin'
what I'm thinkin'?
帕特里克，你在想吗
我在想什么？
Yep.
是的。
Both: It's beautiful.
两人：真漂亮。
SpongeBob?
海绵宝宝？
I waited so long.
我等了这么久。
SpongeBob?
海绵宝宝？
And you broke it.
而你却打破了它。
You O.K., buddy?
你还好吗，伙计？
Yes...
是的...
Yes, I'm ok.
是的，我没事。
: For a sec...
: 一会儿...
You...!
你...！
You ruined my free toy!
你毁了我的免费玩具！
I'm sorry.
对不起。
Maybe if you just...
也许如果你只是...
Ah...!
啊...！
Just keep walking, Squiddy.
继续走吧，鱿鱼。
Don't make eye contact.
不要进行目光接触。
Argh...
啊啊……
: Now to sooth
my frayed nerves.
: 现在来安慰一下
我紧张的神经。
SpongeBob and Patrick:
海绵宝宝和帕特里克：
All right, what's going on?
好吧，发生什么事了？
Why are you two crying?
你们两个为什么哭？
: I, I ate
box, box, box tops...
: 我、我吃了
盒子、盒子、盒子顶……
And then, I'm waiting,
I'm waiting...
然后，我就等着，
我在等...
And then he, he came...
然后他，他来了……
And then we're waiting...
然后我们就等着...
We're waiting...
我们正在等待...
And then, my toy...
然后，我的玩具...
And then you...
然后你...
And then snap...
然后啪...
And then this.
然后这个。
There, now see?
在那里，现在看到了吗？
It's supposed to do that.
它应该这样做。
Hey, my toy's O.K.
嘿，我的玩具没问题。
Good.
好的。
Now will you two be quiet?
现在你们两个能安静点吗？
Look, Patrick,
Squidward fixed it.
看，帕特里克，
章鱼哥修好了它。
How can we ever thank you?
我们该如何感谢你呢？
Yeah, how can we thank you?
是啊，我们该怎么感谢你呢？
Move to another neighborhood.
搬到另一个街区。
Krabby Patties...
蟹黄饼...
Coming right up, sir.
马上就上来，先生。
Meow.
喵。
Gary, what are you doing?
加里，你在做什么？
Meow.
喵。
SpongeBob: Oh, my gosh,
your bowl's empty.
海绵宝宝：哦，天哪，
你的碗空了。
Not to worry, Gare-Gare,
food is on the way.
别担心，Gare-Gare，
食物正在路上。
Faster than you can say...
比你说的还要快...
organic.
有机的。
Meow.
喵。
There ya go, Gary.
就这样吧，加里。
Yuck.
恶心。
Gary, shame on you.
加里，你真丢脸。
I realize you're a bottom
feeder, but have some manners.
我发现你是个底层
喂食者，但要有一定的礼仪。
You know you're not supposed to
eat goop off the ground.
你知道你不应该这样做
吃地上的粘液。
SpongeBob: Now go on and
enjoy your health food.
海绵宝宝：现在继续
享受你的健康食品。
What is this stuff anyway?
这到底是什么东西？
Doesn't seem to be coming off.
好像没下来啊
Ooh, company.
哦，公司。
Hi Sponge...
海绵你好...
Something wrong, Patrick?
有什么问题吗，帕特里克？
SpongeBob, what is that?
海绵宝宝，那是什么？
What's what?
什么是什么？
This!
这！
Aah...!
啊啊……！
P-P-P-Patrick.
帕-帕-帕-帕特里克。
What should I do?
我应该怎么办？
Scratch it like
there's no tomorrow.
刮一下就像
没有明天。
Good idea.
好主意。
Uh, SpongeBob?
呃，海绵宝宝？
Yeah?
是的？
Patrick: I don't
know about this.
帕特里克：我不
了解这一点。
What makes you say that?
是什么让你这么说？
This...
这...
Ah...!
啊...！
It's getting bigger!
越来越大了！
Nothing a little pimple
cream can't cure.
没什么小痘痘
霜不能治愈。
Ah, that's more like it.
啊，这更像是这样。
All better.
一切都好起来了。
See Patrick?
看到帕特里克吗？
Sure do.
当然可以。
Well, I'm gonna
go sit in my hole.
嗯，我要
去我的洞里坐吧。
Catch you later, pal.
稍后见，朋友。
Bye, Patrick.
再见，帕特里克。
La, la, la...
啦啦啦……
Ah, this feels better.
啊，这样感觉好多了。
Let's see...
让我们来看看...
a four letter word.
一个四个字母的单词。
Meaning an uncomfortable
sensation on the dermis, hmm...
表示不舒服的意思
真皮层的感觉，嗯……
Ooh...
哦...
Itch!
痒！
Don't worry, SpongeBob,
everyone gets itchy, swollen
skin rash now and then.
别担心，海绵宝宝，
每个人都会发痒、肿胀
时不时出现皮疹。
Just don't scratch it,
and it'll go away...
只要别刮伤就好
然后它就会消失...
Eventually.
最终。
There, out of sight,
out of mind.
在那里，看不见的地方，
失去理智。
I won't let this minor setback
hinder my fry cooking.
我不会让这个小挫折
妨碍我炒菜。
now nothing can distract me
from fryin' up those patties.
现在没有什么可以分散我的注意力
从煎那些肉饼开始。
Except maybe this
unbearable itchiness.
也许除了这个
难以忍受的瘙痒。
Must... Stop... Scratching!
必须...停止...抓挠！
SpongeBob, ah...!
海绵宝宝，啊……！
SpongeBob.
海绵宝宝。
Huh?
啊？
Oh, hi Squidward.
哦，嗨章鱼哥。
SpongeBob, why are
you all puffy?
海绵宝宝，为什么
你们都浮肿吗？
All whaty?
都什么？
Your skin, SpongeBob, what's
wrong with your skin?
你的皮肤，海绵宝宝，是什么
你的皮肤有问题吗？
Oh that, it's nothing really
Squidward, just a little
blemish, that's all.
哦那个，其实没什么
章鱼哥，一点点
瑕疵，仅此而已。
Aah...!
啊啊……！
That's no blemish...
这不算什么瑕疵吧...
Help me!
帮我！
Oh, I'll help you alright.
哦，我会帮你的。
SWAT team.
特警队。
We'll be right over.
我们马上就过去。
Hold it right there!
就稳住那儿吧！
Dear Neptune's trident.
亲爱的海王星的三叉戟。
This is the most
severe case of ick yet.
这是最
病情严重的还没有。
Stop!
停止！
You fool!
你这个傻瓜！
Do you wanna get infected?
你想被感染吗？
This is a job for
the hazmat division.
这是一份工作
危险品部门。
Get back!
回来吧！
I said get back!
我说回来吧！
Back I say!
我说回来！
What's going on, Squidward?
发生什么事了，章鱼哥？
Ah...!
啊...！
Here's your change, sir.
这是您找的零钱，先生。
Oh why, thank you very much,
young man.
噢，为什么，非常感谢，
年轻人。
What was that?
那是什么？
No, no Mr. Squidward,
that can't be the ick.
不，不，章鱼哥先生，
那不可能是病。
Ooh, where am I?
哦，我在哪儿？
Whoa...!
哇...！
Mmm, hmm, yes...
嗯嗯，是啊……
Who are you people?
你们是谁？
I wanna go home.
我想回家。
You are home, SpongeBob.
你到家了，海绵宝宝。
You just need to stay in this
bubble until the ick clears up.
你只需要留在这个
冒泡直至症状消失。
Where's my snail, Gary?
我的蜗牛在哪里，加里？
We've taken care of your pet.
我们已经照顾好你的宠物了。
Meow.
喵。
Gary?
加里？
Whoa!
哇！
He appears stable, sir.
他看起来很稳定，先生。
All right boys,
let's pack it up.
好吧，孩子们，
我们把它打包吧。
Wow...
哇...
Huh?
啊？
What is this?
这是什么？
Patrick, stop, stop!
帕特里克，停下来，停下来！
You're gonna pop it!
你会弹出它！
Really?
真的吗？
How 'bout if I
squeeze it like this?
如果我怎么样
像这样挤？
Or this?
还是这个？
No!
不！
Or this?
还是这个？
Ah, Patrick!
啊，帕特里克！
How many times
do I have to tell you?
多少次
我必须告诉你吗？
Be careful!
当心！
Sorry.
对不起。
Hey, wanna play a game
of pirate wrestling?
嘿嘿想玩游戏
海盗摔跤？
Sure, let's begin.
当然，让我们开始吧。
Um... Patrick?
嗯...帕特里克？
I win, I win, I win!
我赢了，我赢了，我赢了！
Patrick?
帕特里克？
Go Patrick, go Patrick,
go Patrick.
帕特里克加油，帕特里克加油，
帕特里克去吧。
Patrick!
帕特里克！
What am I gonna do?
我要做什么？
My bubble is destroyed.
我的泡沫被摧毁了。
I've got an idea.
我有一个主意。
There's no time for games, Pat.
没有时间玩游戏了，帕特。
Now think, SpongeBob.
现在想想，海绵宝宝。
The fate of Bikini
Bottom rests in your hands.
比基尼的命运
底部就在你的手中。
Huh?
啊？
Patrick, you're a genius.
帕特里克，你是个天才。
And this one's mobile.
而且这个是手机的。
Now I can go back to work.
现在我可以回去工作了。
Squidward, help!
章鱼哥，救命啊！
Help me flip these patties.
帮我翻转这些馅饼。
We've got growling
stomachs out there.
我们有咆哮
肚子在那里。
No, no, no, no, no, no, no.
不，不，不，不，不，不，不。
Then would it be too much
trouble to ask his
high and mightiness
那么会不会太过分了
麻烦问一下他的
威风凛凛
to take these patties
out to the customers?
拿这些肉饼
出给客户？
: If only
SpongeBob were here.
: 如果只是
海绵宝宝来了。
If SpongeBob were here,
we'd be covered in ick.
如果海绵宝宝在这里的话
我们会浑身恶心。
Lunch is served.
供应午餐。
Eat up kids.
吃饱孩子们。
Ah...
啊...
Why am I so itchy?
为什么我这么痒？
No...
不...
Ahh...!
啊……！
Squidward: SpongeBob
gave me the ick!
章鱼哥：海绵宝宝
让我恶心了！
And I gave it to all you people!
我把它给了你们所有人！
Stay back, you diseased freaks!
退后一步，你们这些病态的怪物！
What's all the commotion about?
到底是为了什么？
The commotion, my dear Krabs, is
regarding the hygiene standards
of your eating establishment,
亲爱的蟹老板，这场骚动是
关于卫生标准
您的餐饮场所，
which appear to be inadequate.
这似乎是不够的。
Inadequate?
不足？
I'll have you know, the staff at
the Krusty Krab take a solemn
pledge to show up
我会让你知道的，工作人员
蟹堡王庄严地举行
承诺出现
everyday of the week clean
and disease free.
一周中的每一天都是干净的
并且无疾病。
SpongeBob: Sorry I'm late,
Mr. Krabs.
海绵宝宝：抱歉我来晚了
蟹老板。
SpongeBob SquarePants...
海绵宝宝方裤...
Returning for duty, sir.
回来执勤了，先生。
Is that what you consider clean
and disease free, Krabby?
这就是你认为的干净吗
没有疾病，克拉比？
I say we ransack this
greasy disease shack.
我说我们搜查这个
油腻病棚。
Who's with me?
谁和我在一起？
I'm with you, you funny
talking fella, come on.
我和你在一起，你很有趣
会说话的家伙，来吧。
It wasn't me, it was Squidward.
不是我，是章鱼哥。
He gave you all the ick.
他给了你所有的恶心。
No, no I didn't.
不，不，我没有。
It was SpongeBob.
这是海绵宝宝。
He's infected the
entire Krusty Krab.
他感染了
整个蟹堡王。
Let us apprehend that
careless contaminator.
让我们明白这一点
粗心的污染者。
meow.
喵。
Stop!
停止！
You're pushing
out more of the ick.
你在推
出了更多的病。
No...!
不...！
stop it!
停下来！
You're ticklin' me, Squidward!
你在逗我呢，章鱼哥！
It's not me, Mr. Krabs.
这不是我，蟹老板。
Gary B. Snail.
加里·B·蜗牛.
Don't you know it's impolite
to feed off of other people
without permission?
你不知道这样很不礼貌吗
以他人为食
未经许可？
He's just doing
his job, SpongeBob.
他只是在做
他的工作，海绵宝宝。
He's a bottom feeder, remember?
他是个底部喂食者，还记得吗？
See?
看？
The little fella
licked me clean.
小家伙
把我舔干净了。
I'm cured, and he'll clean the
ick off any surface.
我痊愈了，他会清理
清除任何表面。
Even squid.
甚至鱿鱼。
Oh, oh, me next.
哦哦，下一个是我。
Where are your manners?
你的礼貌在哪里？
It's ladies first.
这是女士优先。
I believe the expression is
"starfish first".
我相信这个表达是
“海星第一”。
I supersede all of you,
for I have an exotic accent.
我取代了你们所有人
因为我有异国口音。
Hey, hey, hey,
there's no need to fight.
嘿嘿嘿嘿
没有必要去战斗。
'Cause I got a solution
I'll be happy with.
因为我找到了解决办法
我会很高兴的。
Step up to be de-icked, only $5.
赶快去除臭，只需 5 美元。
Now can I get ya a Krabby Patty?
现在我可以给你买一份蟹肉饼吗？
In light of today's events, that
notion is crass and offensive.
鉴于今天发生的事件，
这种想法是粗鲁且令人反感的。
I'll take two please.
请我拿两个。
All right.
好的。
Here ya go, Mr. Krabs.
给你，蟹老板。
Another $5, for
another de-icking.
另外 5 美元，用于
另一个除臭。
Look Gare, you made
me all sparkly.
瞧，Gare，你做到了
我都闪闪发光。
You're the best bottom feeder a
sponge could ever have.
你是最好的底层喂食者
海绵可能曾经有过。
Aye, and a great money
maker you are, too.
是啊，还有一大笔钱
你也是制造者。
Now back to work.
现在回去工作了。